Guide to the James Joyce Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- SERIES II. WRITINGS, 1903-1955; (14 boxes)
  - MUSICAL SETTINGS & ADAPTATIONS
    - FROM DEWY DREAMS, 1924
      F 4 Eugene Bonner Chamber Music XV
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 615.
    - MR. BLOOM AND THE CYCLOPS, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 149)
      F 5 George Antheil Ulysses
    - GOLDENHAIR, 1925
      F 6 Frank Bridge Chamber Music V
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 616
    - SLEEP NOW, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 150)
      F 7 Lee Pattison Chamber Music XXXIV
    - STRINGS IN THE EARTH, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 151)
      F 8 J. Bertram Fox Chamber Music I
    - I HEAR AN ARMY, 1927
      F 9 Sidney Harrison Chamber Music
      XXXVI Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 617
    - LAY OF SOLITUDE, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 152)
      F10 Creighton Allen Chamber Music XXXV
    - SIX SONGS, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 153)
      F11 Eugene Goossens Chamber Music XVI,
      XXVIII, XXIX, XXXIII, XXXV, XXXVI
    - FIVE SONGS FOR VOICE AND PIANO, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 154)
      F12 Israel Citkowitz Chamber Music I,
      IV, VII, XI, XXXI
    - SEVEN POEMS, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 155)
      F13 E. J. Moeran Chamber Music I, VIII,
      X, XVI, XXXI, XXXII, XXXIII 2 copies
      (variant binding)
    - ROSEFRAIL, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 156)
      F14 E. J. Moeran Pomes Penyeach: A
      flower given to my daughter
    - THE JOYCE BOOK
      F15 In: Beinecke Library Iq.J853.P63X.
      J85
    - COS COB SONG VOLUME, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 157)
      F16 Roger Sessions/Israel Citkowitz
      On the beach at Fontana (Pomes
      Penyeach) and Gentle Lady (Chamber
      Music XXVIII)
    - SHE WEEPS OVER RAHOON, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 158)
      F17 Harold Triggs Pomes Penyeach
    - ANNA LIVIA PLURABELLE, 1935
      F18 Hazel Felman Finnegans Wake
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 618.
    - RAIN HAS FALLEN, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      F20 Samuel Barber Chamber Music XXXII
    - SLEEP NOW, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 160)
      F21 Samuel Barber Chamber Music XXXIV
    - I HEAR AN ARMY, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 161)
      F22 Samuel Barber Chamber Music XXXVI
    - A FLOWER GIVEN TO MY DAUGHTER, 1942
      F23 David Diamond Pomes Penyeach
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 619.
    - RAHOON, 1947
      F24 E. J. Moeran Pomes Penyeach
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 620.
    - BRIGID'S SONG, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 162)
      F25 David Diamond A Portrait of the
      Artist as a Young Man
    - A FLOWER GIVEN TO MY DAUGHTER, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 163)
      F26 Albert Roussel Pomes Penyeach
    - ULYSSES, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 164)
      F27 Matyas Seiber Ulysses (Random
      House Edition): p. 682-686
    - RAIN HAS FALLEN ALL THE DAY, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      F28 William R. Smith Chamber Music
      XXXII
    - SIX COMMENTAIRES POUR ULYSSE DE JAMES JOYCE, 1948
      - F29 Thomas de Hartmann Ulysses
    - BID ADIEU, 1949
      F30 James Joyce Chamber Music XI
      Edmund Pendleton
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 622.
    - 4 PIESNI, 1949
      F31 Karol Szymanowski Chamber Music V,
      XIV, XXVIII, XXXIV; photocopies
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 623
    - TRE POEMI, 1950
      F32 Luigi Dallapiccola A flower given
      to my daughter (Pomes Penyeach)
      Manuscript
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 38, folder 624.
    - ALL DAY I HEAR, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 166)
      F33 Sergius Kagen Chamber Music XXXV
    - ALL DAY I HEAR, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 167)
      F34 Gardner Read Chamber Music XXXV
    - SLEEP NOW, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 168)
      F35 Sergius Kagen Chamber Music XXXIV
    - RAIN HAS FALLEN ALL THE DAY, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 169)
      F36 Robert Ward Chamber Music XXXII
    - NUVOLETTA, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 170)
      F37 Samuel Barber Finnegans Wake
    - 4 Songs, 1926, 1927
      Tibor Serly Sleep now; Gentle Lady; All Day; and Silently She's Coming.
      Cf. S & C, p. 163.
  - WORKS ABOUT JOYCE:
    - Bodkin, Thomas NOTES ON A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN Manuscript 2p., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Cahoon, Herbert THE SIGNIFICANCE OF TEXTUAL STUDIES IN MODERN AUTHORS Typescript 17p., 1955 (Box 8, Folder 172)
      Paper read at the English Institute,
      Columbia University, 1955 Sep 8.
    - JUNG ON JAMES JOYCE Typescript 26p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 173)
      Carbon copy
    - Kain, Richard JOYCE AS A REVIEWER Typescript 5p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 174)
      Carbon copy attached
    - Kain, Richard NOTES ON A TRIP TO DUBLIN Typescript, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - 10p. Carbon copy
    - Mason, Ellsworth, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - ALAS, POOR JOYCE! I KNEW HIM Typescript 14p.
      Gift of Mr. Mason
    - Mason, Ellsworth FLIP! FLOP! JOYCE AGAIN Typescript 13p., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Mason, Ellsworth MR. STANISLAUS JOYCE Typescript 13p., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Carbon copy. Accompanied by a TLS from Mr. Mason to Norman H. Pearson, dated, 1954 Feb 20
    - Gift of Mr. Mason
    - Monnier, Adrienne JOYCE ET LE PUBLIC FRANCAIS Manuscript 36p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 179)
      Purchased from Maurice Saillet, 1967,
      with monies from the Beinecke Rare Book
      Endowment Fund.
    - Slocum, John J. and Herbert Cahoon BIBLIOGRAPHY See: SERIES IV.
    - Slocum John J. IN PURSUIT OF JAMES JOYCE Typescript 10p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Slocum, John J. JAMES JOYCE TEN YEARS AFTER Typescript 55p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 181)
      3 drafts with carbons; one 12p., one
      15p., and one 18p.
    - Slocum John J. JAMES JOYCE'S DUBLIN Typescript 13p., 1950 (Box 8, Folder 182)
      Lecture given to the Y.M.H.A. at the
      Poetry Center, Feb 9, 1950.
    - Soupault, Philippe SOUVENIRS DE JAMES JOYCE Manuscript 82p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 183)
      In case with a copy of the first
      edition, 1943.
    - Svevo, Italo ITALO SVEVO ON JAMES JOYCE: EXCERPTS Typescript 24p., 1927 (Box 8, Folder 184)
      English translation
    - Svevo, Italo MR. JAMES JOYCE Typescript 1p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Von Weber, Roland JAMES JOYCE'S ITALIAN LETTERS Typescript 16p. (Box 8, Folder 186)
      English translations of letters in
      the Slocum collection.
- SERIES III. SPECIAL FILES, 1884-1969; (36 boxes)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT JOYCE
    - Joyce as a singer and actor
      - 1901-1939 (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - Joyce as a literary figure
      - undated (Box 9, Folder 188)
      - 1915 (Box 9, Folder 189)
      - 1917 (Box 9, Folder 190)
      - 1918 (Box 9, Folder 191)
      - 1919 (Box 9, Folder 192)
      - 1920 (Box 9, Folder 193)
      - 1922 (Box 9, Folder 194)
      - 1923 (Box 9, Folder 195)
      - 1924
      - 1925 The Irish Statesman: 1925 Oct 24, with Joyce's manuscript notes. (Box 9, Folder 196)
      - 1926 (Box 9, Folder 197)
      - 1927 (Box 9, Folder 198)
      - 1928 (Box 9, Folder 199)
      - 1929 (Box 9, Folder 200)
      - 1930
      - 1931 (Box 9, Folder 201)
      - 1932 (Box 10, Folder 202)
      - 1933 (Box 10, Folder 203)
      - 1934 (Box 10, Folder 204)
      - 1935 (Box 10, Folder 205)
      - 1936 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      - 1937 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      - 1938 (Box 10, Folder 208)
      - 1939 (Box 10, Folder 209)
      - 1941 (Box 10, Folder 210)
      - 1942 (Box 10, Folder 211)
      - 1943 (Box 10, Folder 212)
      - 1944 (Box 10, Folder 213)
      - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 214)
      - 1947 (Box 10, Folder 215)
      - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 216)
      - 1949 The clippings in this folder have no date other than 1949. (Box 10, Folder 217)
      - 1949 January-December (Box 10, Folder 218)
      - 1950 The clippings in this folder have no date other than 1950. (Box 11, Folder 219)
      - 1950 January-December (Box 11, Folder 220)
      - 1951 The clippings in this folder have no date other than 1951. (Box 11, Folder 221)
      - 1951 January-June (Box 11, Folder 222)
      - 1951 July-December (Box 11, Folder 223)
      - 1952 The clippings in this folder have no date other than 1952. (Box 11, Folder 224)
      - 1952 January-December (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - 1953 The clippings in this folder have no date other than 1953. (Box 11, Folder 226)
      - 1953 January-December
      - 1954 (Box 12, Folder 227)
      - 1955 (Box 12, Folder 228)
      - 1956 (Box 12, Folder 229)
      - 1957 (Box 12, Folder 230)
      - 1958 (Box 12, Folder 231)
      - 1959 (Box 12, Folder 232)
      - 1960 (Box 12, Folder 233)
      - 1961 (Box 12, Folder 234)
      - 1962 (Box 12, Folder 235)
      - 1964 (Box 12, Folder 236)
      - 1965 (Box 12, Folder 237)
      - 1966 (Box 13, Folder 238)
      - 1967 (Box 13, Folder 239)
      - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 240)
      - 1969- (Box 13, Folder 241)
      - Misc. (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT MEMBERS OF JOYCE'S FAMILY
    - George Joyce (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - John Stanislaus Joyce (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - Mrs. Mary Jane Joyce (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - May Joyce Monaghan (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - Nora Joyce (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - Stanislaus Joyce (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - Stephen James Joyce (Box 13, Folder 249)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT WORKS BY JOYCE
    - Book reviews (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - CHAMBER MUSIC (Box 13, Folder 251)
    - DAY OF RABBLEMENT (Box 13, Folder 252)
    - ECCE PUER (Box 13, Folder 253)
    - GIACOMO JOYCE
    - POMES PENYEACH (Box 13, Folder 254)
    - DUBLINERS
      - 1914 (Box 13, Folder 255)
      - 1917 (Box 13, Folder 256)
      - 1926 (Box 13, Folder 257)
      - 1932 (Box 13, Folder 258)
      - 1950 (Box 13, Folder 259)
      - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 260)
      - 1953 (Box 13, Folder 261)
      - 1954 (Box 13, Folder 262)
      - 1965 (Box 13, Folder 263)
    - EXILES
      - undated (Box 14, Folder 264)
      - 1917 (Box 14, Folder 265)
      - 1918 (Box 14, Folder 266)
      - 1919 (Box 14, Folder 267)
      - 1920 (Box 14, Folder 268)
      - 1925 (Box 14, Folder 269)
      - 1926 Including report of the Reading Committee of the Incorporated Stage Society (Box 14, Folder 270)
      - 1936 (Box 14, Folder 271)
      - 1948 (Box 14, Folder 272)
      - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 273)
      - 1956 (Box 14, Folder 274)
      - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 275)
      - 1959 (Box 14, Folder 276)
      - 1964 (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - FINNEGANS WAKE
      - undated (Box 14, Folder 278)
      - 1925 (Box 14, Folder 279)
      - 1926 (Box 14, Folder 280)
      - 1927 (Box 14, Folder 281)
      - 1928 (Box 14, Folder 282)
      - 1929 (Box 14, Folder 283)
      - 1930 (Box 14, Folder 284)
      - 1931 (Box 14, Folder 285)
      - 1932 (Box 14, Folder 286)
      - 1933 (Box 14, Folder 287)
      - 1934 (Box 14, Folder 288)
      - 1937 (Box 14, Folder 289)
      - 1938 (Box 14, Folder 290)
      - 1939 January-May
      - 1939 June-December (Box 14, Folder 291)
      - 1940 (Box 14, Folder 292)
      - 1947
      - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 293)
      - 1951 (Box 15, Folder 294)
      - 1954 (Box 15, Folder 295)
      - 1955 (Box 15, Folder 296)
      - 1956 (Box 15, Folder 297)
      - 1957 (Box 15, Folder 298)
      - 1958 (Box 15, Folder 299)
      - 1960 (Box 15, Folder 300)
      - 1962 (Box 15, Folder 301)
      - 1965 (Box 15, Folder 302)
      - 1966 (Box 15, Folder 303)
      - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN
      - undated There is a Reader's Report on A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man from Duckworth & Co. in SERIES I, Box 4, Folder 20 (Box 16, Folder 305)
      - 1916 (Box 16, Folder 306)
      - 1917 January-April
      - 1917 May (Box 16, Folder 307)
      - 1917 June-December (Box 16, Folder 308)
      - 1918 (Box 16, Folder 309)
      - 1919 (Box 16, Folder 310)
      - 1920 (Box 16, Folder 311)
      - 1922 (Box 16, Folder 312)
      - 1924 (Box 16, Folder 313)
      - 1925 (Box 16, Folder 314)
      - 1926 (Box 16, Folder 315)
      - 1941 (Box 16, Folder 316)
      - 1952 (Box 16, Folder 317)
      - 1954 (Box 16, Folder 318)
      - 1960 (Box 16, Folder 319)
      - 1963 (Box 16, Folder 320)
    - ULYSSES
      - undated (Box 17, Folder 321)
      - 1918 (Box 17, Folder 322)
      - 1919 (Box 17, Folder 323)
      - 1920 (Box 17, Folder 324)
      - 1921 1921 Feb 28: Mr. Sumner's glorious victory, from the N.Y. Tribune is accompanied by a copy in Joyce's hand (Box 17, Folder 325)
      - 1922 January-March (Box 17, Folder 326)
      - 1922 April
      - 1922 May-August (Box 17, Folder 327)
      - 1922 September-December (Box 17, Folder 328)
      - 1923 (Box 17, Folder 329)
      - 1924 (Box 17, Folder 330)
      - 1925 (Box 18, Folder 331)
      - 1926 (Box 18, Folder 332)
      - 1927 1927 Feb 2: printed letter about Samuel Roth's pirated edition of ULYSSES; with calling card, signed by James Joyce. (Box 18, Folder 333)
      - 1928 (Box 18, Folder 334)
      - 1929 (Box 18, Folder 335)
      - 1930 (Box 18, Folder 336)
      - 1931 (Box 18, Folder 337)
      - 1932 (Box 18, Folder 338)
      - 1933
      - 1934 (Box 18, Folder 339)
      - 1935 (Box 19, Folder 340)
      - 1936 (Box 19, Folder 341)
      - 1937 (Box 19, Folder 342)
      - 1938 (Box 19, Folder 343)
        [this folder is missing its contents]
      - 1939 (Box 19, Folder 344)
      - 1941 (Box 19, Folder 345)
      - 1950 (Box 19, Folder 346)
      - 1951 (Box 19, Folder 347)
      - 1952 (Box 19, Folder 348)
      - 1953 (Box 19, Folder 349)
      - 1954 (Box 19, Folder 350)
      - 1955 (Box 19, Folder 351)
      - 1956 January-May (Box 19, Folder 352)
      - 1956 June-December (Box 19, Folder 353)
      - 1957 January-May (Box 20, Folder 354)
      - 1957 June-December (Box 20, Folder 355)
      - 1958 (Box 20, Folder 356)
      - 1959 (Box 20, Folder 357)
      - 1960 (Box 20, Folder 358)
      - 1965 (Box 20, Folder 359)
      - 1967 (Box 20, Folder 360)
      - Misc. (Box 20, Folder 361)
      - Misc. (Box 20, Folder 362)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT ADAPTATIONS OF WORKS BY JOYCE:
    - CHAMBER MUSIC (Box 21, Folder 363)
    - DUBLINERS (Box 21, Folder 364)
    - EXILES
      See: Clippings about works by Joyce, Box 13, folders 264-277
    - FINNEGANS WAKE (Box 21, Folder 365)
    - POMES PENYEACH (Box 21, Folder 366)
    - A PORTRAIT OF THE ARTIST AS A YOUNG MAN (Box 21, Folder 367)
    - ULYSSES
      1924 Feb 22: Chicago Tribune review of Cyclops has a note by James Joyce
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 40, folder 636.
    - Works (Box 21, Folder 368)
    - Misc. (Box 21, Folder 369)
    - Misc. (Box 21, Folder 370)
  - CLIPPINGS AND REVIEWS OF WORKS ABOUT JOYCE
    - Beckett, Samuel, et. al. OUR EXAGMINATION (1929) (Box 21, Folder 371)
    - Blamires, Harry THE BLOOMSDAY BOOK (1966) (Box 21, Folder 372)
    - Budgen, Frank JAMES JOYCE AND THE MAKING OF "ULYSSES" (1934) (Box 21, Folder 373)
    - Burgess, Anthony HERE COMES EVERYBODY (1965) (Box 21, Folder 374)
    - Collins, Joseph THE DOCTOR LOOKS AT LITERATURE (1923) (Box 21, Folder 375)
    - Colum, Mary and Padraic OUR FRIEND JAMES JOYCE (1959) (Box 21, Folder 376)
    - Connolly, Thomas E JAMES JOYCE'S SCRIBBLEDEHOBBLE (1961) (Box 21, Folder 377)
    - Daiches, David THE NOVEL AND THE MODERN WORLD (1960) (Box 21, Folder 378)
    - Duff, Charles JAMES JOYCE AND THE PLAIN READER (1932) (Box 21, Folder 379)
    - Ellmann, Richard JAMES JOYCE (1959) (Box 21, Folder 380)
    - Ellmann, Richard LETTERS OF JAMES JOYCE, Volumes II and III (1967) (Box 21, Folder 381)
    - Ervine, John G. SOME IMPRESSIONS OF MY ELDERS (1923) (Box 21, Folder 382)
    - Freund and Carleton JAMES JOYCE IN PARIS (1966) (Box 21, Folder 383)
    - Gilbert, Stuart LETTERS OF JAMES JOYCE, Volume I (1957) (Box 21, Folder 384)
    - Gilbert, Stuart JAMES JOYCE'S "ULYSSES" (1931) (Box 21, Folder 385)
    - Gillet, Louis CLAYBOOK FOR JAMES JOYCE (1959) (Box 21, Folder 386)
    - Gillet, Louis. DU COTE DE CHEZ JOYCE (1925) [In: Revue de Deux Monde, 1-8, 1925] (Box 21, Folder 387)
    - Givens, Sean JAMES JOYCE: TWO DECADES OF CRITICISM (1950) (Box 21, Folder 388)
    - Glasheen, Adaline A CENSUS OF FINNEGANS WAKE (Box 21, Folder 389)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John IT ISN'T THIS TIME OF YEAR AT ALL (1954) (Box 21, Folder 390)
    - Golding, Louis JAMES JOYCE (1933) (Box 21, Folder 391)
    - Gorman, Herbert JAMES JOYCE: A DEFINITIVE BIOGRAPHY (1941) (Box 21, Folder 392)
    - Gorman, Herbert JAMES JOYCE: HIS FIRST FORTY YEARS (1924) (Box 21, Folder 393)
    - INTRODUCING JAMES JOYCE (1943) (Box 22, Folder 394)
    - JAMES JOYCE YEARBOOK (Box 22, Folder 395)
    - THE JOYCE BOOK (1933) (Box 22, Folder 396)
    - Joyce, Stanislaus MY BROTHER'S KEEPER (1958) (Box 22, Folder 397)
    - Kain, Richard M. FABULOUS VOYAGER (1947) (Box 22, Folder 398)
    - Legouis and Cazamian A HISTORY OF ENGLISH LITERATURE (1933) (Box 22, Folder 399)
    - Levin, Harry JAMES JOYCE: A CRITICAL INTRODUCTION (1942) (Box 22, Folder 400)
    - Lewis, Wyndham THE ENEMY: A REVIEW OF ART AND LITERATURE (1922) (Box 22, Folder 401)
    - Loehrich, Rolf THE SECRET OF ULYSSES (Box 22, Folder 402)
    - McKerrow, Consuelo THE PURLIEU OF VENUS (1949) (Box 22, Folder 403)
    - Magalaner, Marvin A JAMES JOYCE MISCELLANY (1957) (Box 22, Folder 404)
    - Magalaner and Kain JOYCE: THE MAN, THE WORK, THE REPUTATION (1956) (Box 22, Folder 405)
    - Morse, Josiah THE DISOBEDIENT ARTIST (1957) (Box 22, Folder 406)
    - Morse, Josiah THE SYMPATHETIC ALIEN (1959) (Box 22, Folder 407)
    - Muir, Edwin TRANSITION (1925) (Box 22, Folder 408)
    - Noon, William T. JOYCE AND AQUINAS (1957) (Box 22, Folder 409)
    - Olson, Charles HUMAN UNIVERSE AND OTHER ESSAYS (Box 22, Folder 410)
    - Raleigh, John H. A FULL MOON IN MARCH (1955) (In: Modern Language Notes, March 1955) (Box 22, Folder 411)
    - Read, Forrest POUND/JOYCE (1968) (Box 22, Folder 412)
    - Rickword SCRUTINIES (1929) (Box 22, Folder 413)
    - Scholes, Robert E THE CORNELL JOYCE COLLECTION (1962) (Box 22, Folder 414)
    - Spielberg, Peter JAMES JOYCE'S MANUSCRIPTS AND LETTERS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF BUFFALO (1963) (Box 22, Folder 415)
    - Staley, Thomas F. JAMES JOYCE TODAY (Box 22, Folder 416)
    - Sullivan, Kevin JOYCE AMONG THE JESUITS (1958) (Box 22, Folder 417)
    - Svevo, Italo JAMES JOYCE (1953) (Box 22, Folder 418)
    - Waldock, A. J. JAMES JOYCE AND OTHERS (1937) (Box 22, Folder 419)
    - Misc. (Box 22, Folder 420)
  - LECTURE PROGRAMS, ETC. IN WHICH JOYCE TOOK PART
    - Unidentified Concert program 1904 Aug 22 (Box 22, Folder 421)
    - Bray Boat Club Concert program 1888 Jun 26 (Box 22, Folder 422)
    - Déjeuner Ulysse Menu 1929 (Box 22, Folder 423)
    - The Garden Club Menu n.y. Apr 5 (Box 22, Folder 424)
    - St. Brigid's Panoramic Choir and Fingall Ladies' Orchestra Concert program 1904 May 14 (Box 22, Folder 425)
    - Universita Popolare Triestina Lecture program 1911-1912 (Box 22, Folder 426)
    - University College Literary and Historical Society Program 1899-1900 (Box 22, Folder 427)
  - PROGRAMS & PROSPECTI ABOUT JOYCE
    - The Caxton Club Lecture program 1953 Nov 21 (Box 22, Folder 428)
    - The English Institute Lecture program 1955 Sep, 1957 Sep (Box 22, Folder 429)
    - Forum 49/4 Seasons Book Shop Lecture program 1949 Aug 4 (Box 22, Folder 430)
    - James Joyce Symposium: I Prospectus 1967 (Box 22, Folder 431)
    - La Maison des Amis des Livres Lecture program 1921- (Box 22, Folder 432)
    - Michigan Academy of Sciences, Arts, and Letters Lecture program 1953 Apr (Box 22, Folder 433)
    - New School of Social Research Prospectus 1953 (Box 22, Folder 434)
    - New York Public Library Lecture program 1953 (Box 22, Folder 435)
    - Poetry Center Lecture programs (Box 22, Folder 436)
    - The Rowfant Club Lecture program n.y. Apr 28 (Box 22, Folder 437)
    - University of Toronto: Oral examination program Prospectus 1960 May (Box 22, Folder 438)
    - University of Virginia Prospectus 1947 (Box 22, Folder 439)
    - Wayne University Prospectus 1953 (Box 22, Folder 440)
    - Yale Library Associates Lecture program 1951 (Box 22, Folder 441)
    - Zurich. Universität Lecture program 1966 Jun (Box 22, Folder 442)
    - Misc. (Box 22, Folder 443)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF JOYCE AND HIS FAMILY:
    - James Joyce 1884 Anderson, p. 13 (Box 23, Folder 444)
    - James Joyce 1888 (Box 23, Folder 445)
    - James Joyce 1902 Dec 15 Postal card to J. F. Byrne S & C: E 1 e ii
      See: SERIES I, Box 1, Folder 5
    - James Joyce 1902 Anderson, p. 35 Graduation group from University College (Box 23, Folder 446)
    - James Joyce (by C.P. Curran) 1904 Anderson, p. 53 (Box 23, Folder 447)
    - The Joyce Family 1915 In a restaurant (Box 23, Folder 448)
    - The Joyce Family 1915 Anderson, p. 87 (Box 23, Folder 449)
    - James Joyce 1915 Anderson, p. 82 Inscribed to Michael Healy (Box 23, Folder 450)
    - James Joyce 1916 Inscribed to Mrs. Barnacle (Box 23, Folder 451)
    - James Joyce 1920 Signed (Box 23, Folder 452)
    - James Joyce 1920 Photograph of a drawing by Wyndham Lewis (Box 23, Folder 453)
    - James Joyce 1920 Inscribed to Carlo Linati (Box 23, Folder 454)
    - James Joyce ca. 1920 Anderson, p. 105 (Box 23, Folder 455)
    - James Joyce ca. 1920 Anderson, p. 111 (Box 23, Folder 456)
    - Nora Joyce ca. 1920 Anderson, p. 110 (Box 23, Folder 457)
    - James and Nora Joyce 1930 Anderson, p. 117 (Box 23, Folder 458)
    - James Joyce 1935 Photograph of a drawing by Sean O'Sullivan (Box 23, Folder 459)
    - James Joyce and Paul Léon 1936 (Box 23, Folder 460)
    - James Joyce and Paul Léon 1936 Anderson, p. 125 (Box 23, Folder 461)
    - James Joyce 1936 Seven (7) photographs taken by Liphitzki (Box 23, Folder 462)
    - James Joyce 1937 Photograph of a sketch by Sean O'Sullivan (Box 23, Folder 463)
    - Four generations of Joyces n.d. John Stanislaus, James, George, and Stephen James Joyce (Box 23, Folder 464)
    - James Joyce n.d. With an unidentified man (Box 23, Folder 465)
    - James Joyce n.d. By H. Martinie (Box 23, Folder 466)
    - James Joyce n.d. Photograph of a portrait by Jacques-Emile Blanche (Box 23, Folder 467)
    - James Joyce Miscellaneous pictures (Box 23, Folder 468)
    - Joyce's grave Two views (Box 23, Folder 469)
    - Lucia Joyce 1926 (Box 23, Folder 470)
    - Lucia Joyce n.d. Anderson, p. 102 (Box 23, Folder 471)
    - Lucia Joyce n.d. (Box 23, Folder 472)
    - Michael Healy n.d. Anderson, p. 81 (Box 23, Folder 473)
    - Six girls n.d. Unidentified (Box 23, Folder 474)
    - Girl reading Ulysses n.d.
    - Magazine and newspaper pictures of James Joyce (Box 23, Folder 475)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT PORTRAITS OF JOYCE BY:
    - Jacques-Emile Blanche (Box 23, Folder 476)
    - Sava Botzaris (Box 23, Folder 477)
    - Brancusi (Box 23, Folder 478)
    - Stuart Davis (Box 23, Folder 479)
    - Augustus John (Box 23, Folder 480)
    - Patrick Tuohy (Box 23, Folder 481)
    - Misc. (Box 23, Folder 482)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT PEOPLE ASSOCIATED WITH JOYCE
    - Margaret C. Anderson (Box 23, Folder 483)
    - Clive Cary (Box 23, Folder 484)
    - Henry Crew Crosby (Box 23, Folder 485)
    - Edouard Dujardin (Box 23, Folder 486)
    - T. S. Eliot (Box 23, Folder 487)
    - The English Players (Box 23, Folder 488)
    - Hubert Foss (Box 23, Folder 489)
    - Michael Healy (Box 24, Folder 490)
    - B. W. Huebsch (Box 24, Folder 491)
    - Eugene Jolas (Box 24, Folder 492)
    - Wyndham Lewis (Box 24, Folder 493)
    - Carlo Linati (Box 24, Folder 494)
    - John McCormack (Box 24, Folder 495)
    - Adolph Mann (Box 24, Folder 496)
    - Ezra Pound (Box 24, Folder 497)
    - John Quinn (Box 24, Folder 498)
    - Grant Richards (Box 24, Folder 499)
    - John Rodker (Box 24, Folder 500)
    - Samuel Roth (Box 24, Folder 501)
    - Matyas Seiber (Box 24, Folder 502)
    - Sullivan (Box 24, Folder 503)
    - Italo Svevo (Box 24, Folder 504)
    - Virginia Woolf (Box 24, Folder 505)
    - William Butler Yeats (Box 24, Folder 506)
    - Misc. (Box 24, Folder 507)
  - CLIPPINGS ABOUT PLACES ASSOCIATED WITH JOYCE
    - Ireland (Box 24, Folder 508)
    - Dublin (Box 24, Folder 509)